<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rants &amp; Stories on The Pile</title>
    <link>https://thepileTKSM.com/rants-and-stories/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rants &amp; Stories on The Pile</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 01:28:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://thepileTKSM.com/rants-and-stories/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 4 Villains: Love Island UK</title>
      <link>https://thepileTKSM.com/rants-and-stories/top-5-villains-love-island-uk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 01:28:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thepileTKSM.com/rants-and-stories/top-5-villains-love-island-uk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ohhhhhh BABY I’ve been waiting for this one. I’ve been kicking a list around in my head for quite some time, but it’s time to make it official. I’ll be leaving out the U.S. versions since I didn’t watch all of it and what I saw disgusted me. I know people like that; it hits too close to home. The Aussies were generally too chill to achieve peak villainy &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ApMwvtT1plw&#34;&gt;but still had their moments&lt;/a&gt;. But those damned Brits, stuck on their rainy little island, unsurprisingly dredged up some horrible people over six series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s important to note seasons 1 and 2 were in another league when it comes to toxicity. This was before the show really hit it big and producers let more fly, such as on-camera sex, unlimited drinks, cartons of cigs, etc. From season 3 on, it mostly turned into an influencer convention with less MA-rated content, smoking and drinking. It also became more tame–and rightfully so–as former islanders spoke out on how their mental health suffered in that environment. There&amp;rsquo;s been a lot &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theringer.com/tv/2019/7/8/20682978/love-island-reality-tv-mental-health&#34;&gt;written and said&lt;/a&gt; about how lacking Love Island is with their post-show mental health care, so while this list is all in good fun, it&amp;rsquo;s important to acknowledge when people who&amp;rsquo;ve shown more of themselves on international TV than 99.9% of us ever will (comes with the territory, granted) are not being properly cared for after the fact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/bkZBYQ7mnrQ&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does it take to become a villain on a show like this? For me, it comes down to a couple things. Emotional immaturity almost always plays a factor. Liars are the worst. Cockiness and insecurity often lead to shadiness. Stupidity always works against these people. But the manipulators are the worst–the ones who gaslight, emotionally bankrupt their partners, play mind games and are ruthlessly self-centered. So without any further ado, let’s go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Honorable Mentions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://giphy.com/embed/1lwtvMe0X5gaXhSA4O&#34; width=&#34;480&#34; height=&#34;270&#34; frameBorder=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;giphy-embed&#34; allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://giphy.com/gifs/LoveIslandAU-season-1-1lwtvMe0X5gaXhSA4O&#34;&gt;via GIPHY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eden (Australia Season 1):&lt;/strong&gt; This short-tempered, emotionally stunted prison guard stuck with his partner Erin from day 1 and eventually finished second. Along the way, he shouted down Tayla, tried to fight a smaller man, pissed and moaned constantly and was generally a brat. He and Erin split after &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4ClNdVzRaJk&#34;&gt;she said the relationship became abusive&lt;/a&gt;; he denies it, but where there&amp;rsquo;s this sort of smoke, there&amp;rsquo;s usually fire. Eden claims Erin painted him as an “aggressive, angry, threatening person” and that he isn’t really that guy. I’d like to let Eden know that’s exactly how he came across on the show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://giphy.com/embed/l0IyiUgDajtMAxumY&#34; width=&#34;480&#34; height=&#34;270&#34; frameBorder=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;giphy-embed&#34; allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://giphy.com/gifs/love-island-stirring-l0IyiUgDajtMAxumY&#34;&gt;via GIPHY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Javi (Season 2):&lt;/strong&gt; I’m sure he’d be on the real list had he stuck around any longer, but this desperate little worm was first man voted off that season. I actually liked how, at first, he would get in the confessional and speak his mind, but then there’s the matter of what was on his mind. He was, hands-down, one of the most toxic dudes on the show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/UtG32eFdN2M&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Naomi (Season 1):&lt;/strong&gt; An ice queen in the classic sense, Naomi wrapped her younger partner Josh (a full-blown douche in his own right) so tightly around her finger it killed what few brain cells he had left. He stood no chance, but Naomi got greedy, got caught in a few lies and fans and islanders alike turned on her. All she really did was go after other girls’ guys, lead Josh on and lie (small potatoes in the villa), but because she did it with her nose in the air, it rubbed everyone the wrong way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;*It&amp;rsquo;s damn near impossible to find any video of her, or any real video from Season 1.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://giphy.com/embed/l2ABnYMQljmmB1a15z&#34; width=&#34;388&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; frameBorder=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;giphy-embed&#34; allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://giphy.com/gifs/thexfactoruk-transparent-xfactor-xfactorcelebrity-l2ABnYMQljmmB1a15z&#34;&gt;via GIPHY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eyal (Season 4):&lt;/strong&gt; This guy was less of a villain and more an insufferable, pseudo-spiritual douche. He’s the guy that went to a couple therapy sessions and figured out how to sound emotionally mature while still behaving like a middle schooler. Lucky for him, he got mad at the nicest dude on the show (Dr. Alex) for going after a girl he was interested in after Eyal…did that exact thing to Alex days before. He showed his true colors–insecure, mostly–the second he got pressed and was gone not longer after. He also acted like a weirdo the whole time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/dtfw8Ud6I8Y&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://giphy.com/embed/TgJ388Ck44nUid5aYu&#34; width=&#34;480&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; frameBorder=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;giphy-embed&#34; allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://giphy.com/gifs/missguided-georgia-TgJ388Ck44nUid5aYu&#34;&gt;via GIPHY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Georgia-&lt;/strong&gt; I think Georgia was 20 when she showed up on the island, and you could tell. It wasn’t even original–there was a nastier, crazier version of Georgia (the next entrant on this list) on a previous season. She was smart enough to know how to get what she wanted, but too petulant to know how to act when she didn’t. Her &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lLqdd16b7vw&#34;&gt;#1 catchphrase was loyalty&lt;/a&gt;, and her M.O. was treating everyone like crap. It was a classic example of demanding what you don’t offer in return. She threw fits, popped off at people, couldn’t handle a drink and instigated, but she found her man in Sam. She convinced him to leave the villa with her so she could…cheat on him with her ex and then &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/TyFQ9Y5d1WE?start=480&#34;&gt;lie/gaslight Sam about it&lt;/a&gt; during the Christmas reunion. She also &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Y9DVIWiZ0oU&#34;&gt;kissed a guy on a date&lt;/a&gt; while still in the villa before flat-out lying about it in front of everyone. She stuck around long enough to make a serious impression and have an argument with nearly everyone, so she makes the cut over the other HMs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Fk3d95EvvPU&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://giphy.com/embed/l4FGAfq1lhgT5gQw0&#34; width=&#34;480&#34; height=&#34;270&#34; frameBorder=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;giphy-embed&#34; allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://giphy.com/gifs/awkward-loveisland-kady-l4FGAfq1lhgT5gQw0&#34;&gt;via GIPHY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kady (Season 2)-&lt;/strong&gt; The original Georgia from season 2, Kady was also a liar, but her brand was emotional manipulation. Like Georgia, Kady was 20 when she showed up on the show and took a shine to an older man (in this case Scott). Though he was far from faultless in their constant fighting, Kady provoked most of it. She played his insecurities to her advantage and then swooped in to keep stringing him along before Scott could cobble together enough brain cells to realize she was making him happy AND miserable (or decide to leave her). She LOVED to argue and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_s-mCc7hcyA&#34;&gt;pick fights&lt;/a&gt;–mostly with Scott, but &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TEmOIKp55Go&#34;&gt;anyone could catch those hands&lt;/a&gt;. The defining moment was her having a full-blown meltdown when a new girl came in and invited Scott out on a date, as is often custom. Nothing happened, but she called the girl some nasty names and told Scott what he could go do with himself (mind you, bro had no say in any of this). Meanwhile, Kady had done a bit of flirting, dating and rubbernecking of her own while still “with” Scott. It&amp;rsquo;s one of the most crystal-clear example of unabashed hypocrisy on a show full of hypocrites, and Kady is probably the reason they continue casting 20/21-year-olds–they stir the pot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/kHgjR52hHDY?start=325&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Alberti Twins (Season 1)-&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3gB_7gsohWo&#34;&gt;These guys were just huge tools&lt;/a&gt;, not much else too it. They were too stupid to lie their way in, and they had two cracks at it. All the while, the twins were talking prodigious amounts of sh*t about how they were “real men” with money and the whole situation were beneath them. They were extremely rude to all the women and had excuses galore for all of it. Facially, they were some of the ugliest dudes that have ever been on the show, pulled up in matching suits like the herbs they were and called themselves the Italian Stallions despite being painfully British. They were unwatchable; I have no idea why they came back for a second round of dinner dates at the end when it was clear everyone already hated them. I guess they needed huge villains for season 1 and found them, but seriously, there was not a single redeemable moment or quality for either of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/3gB_7gsohWo&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;*There isn&amp;rsquo;t much video on YouTube to help me illustrate my point, but I&amp;rsquo;m not wrong. Go look on Reddit if you really care.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://giphy.com/embed/3oKIPwWEgGPrEq13O0&#34; width=&#34;480&#34; height=&#34;270&#34; frameBorder=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;giphy-embed&#34; allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://giphy.com/gifs/johnny-love-island-itv2-3oKIPwWEgGPrEq13O0&#34;&gt;via GIPHY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jonny (Season 3)-&lt;/strong&gt; A literal man baby, but the kind that’s lived enough life to think they have all the answers. Jonny wormed his way in with Camila (the humanitarian ordinance disposal worker who &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3scaU7ZHyXY&#34;&gt;deserved so much better than this show&lt;/a&gt;) by playing up how cultured he was. For him, that mostly just meant he got a lot of money and used it as an excuse to be a prick. Camila figured it out pretty early and took a step back after Jonny offered a detailed explanation on why he doesn’t believe in feminism (after she correctly defined it for him) or think work conditions are unfair for modern women. But his masterpiece was how he perfectly he proved her right after the fact. Jonny ended up hitting the destruct button on him and Camila instead of trying to learn, listen, be better, etc. He did so because &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jIPpdJ-xgGM&#34;&gt;a younger woman caught his eye&lt;/a&gt;. He said he did it because he wanted things to go faster, wanted more excitement and, in his words, felt like he could be more himself around her. “Be himself,” of course, meaning be a moody, dour, sexist, boring, condescending, stupid loser. Then Theo showed up, expressed interest in Tyla and turned Jonny into a puddle. Being cocky, Theo noticed this and immediately provoked Jonny, exposing the hairy doof as hugely insecure and an enormous fake tough guy. All Jonny did was bitch about Theo, bitch about Tyla, smoke cigs and look way softer than everyone else. He wins, by a mile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/e6Bl_DCUqAo&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foul Balling</title>
      <link>https://thepileTKSM.com/rants-and-stories/foul-balling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 01:40:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thepileTKSM.com/rants-and-stories/foul-balling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a kid at baseball games, nothing excited me more than the remote possibility that I’d get my hands on a foul ball. The game itself? Boring and long. The players? Too far away, and usually not pros. Other fans? Drunk, sweaty, uninteresting. Gift shop? Mom says no, Dad says ask Mom. All those things I appreciate now, but they are tough to sell on an 8-year-old (except the gift shop). Still, by that point I knew how to catch a baseball. I knew they sometimes ended up in the stands during the game. And most importantly, I knew I wanted one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took me some time to make it happen. None of my early trips to Fenway Park yielded any luck, mostly because we were stuffed deep in right field, many rows up from the Pesky Pole. Older me would come to know that as a tough spot to hit a baseball. None of my trips to Fenway ever ended with a ball in hand, even after I swapped out the glove for a beer. To be fair, I only went to three or four during that time (the “bring your glove” era) and never had the favorable foul ball seats. But because I was so keen to catch one, I ended up glued to the game action and begging to stay until the last pitch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/TeKtnvh5_6k&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Fenway and the MLB a lost cause, I moved down to AAA. Keeping it within the Red Sox organization, my family made several trips down to Pawtucket, RI to watch the Paw Sox. The team was good and tickets were cheap–the ideal summer outing for the whole fam. The park, on the other hand, was ugly and plopped into a random sector of the city. Minor league baseball is supposed to be a bit quaint, a bit old-timey, and that may be true throughout the lower levels (AA, A, etc.). But because the Paw Sox had the money and Rhode Island has no pro sports, they gave it all the ugly updates the early 21st century had to offer. For us, that meant a below-average stadium that was always scorching hot and lacking shade with oddly steep banked seating ringing the infield. Better seats and a smaller stadium made no difference, and I was routinely skunked. We did one a summer for about four years, and all I had to show for it were sunburns and those little plastic helmets they use as ice cream bowls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the drought soon ended as I climbed further down the ladder. The Cape Cod Baseball League is the premier destination for…top collegiate players to keep their skills sharp playing summer ball. There’s something funny to me about a bunch of kids who grew up in the South and play for SEC schools scooping ice cream and living in the least Southern place in the world–Cape Cod. There’s only one team that isn’t physically on the Cape, and that’s the team closest to me. The Wareham Gatemen play behind the town’s public high school–a big high school, but a high school nonetheless. Their field was what you’d expect; two banks of wooden bleachers for the home fans, one bank for the visitors on the other side, a small announcer’s box behind the plate, merch table, snack shack and little else. Aside from the visiting bullpen cut into the side of a hill in left field, the most notable feature was the infield. Instead of regular brown dirt, Spillane Field sports some kind of gravelly grey mixture masquerading as dirt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ksg0ahFv2K0&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Weird hot dog eating aside, this is a pretty good lay of the land at Spillane Field&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from the bleachers flanking home plate, the rest of the area surrounding the field was open. The school ended up blocking much of the third base side, but you could run up and down the corridor between building and field. Down the first base side was nothing but grass and woods. The games were free to attend, so we went a lot. By this point, I needed a foul ball badly. So badly, in fact, that when one started bouncing my way down the aforementioned corridor, I body-checked a younger, smaller child into the side of the school to get my hands on it. Unluckily, his dad watched me do it. In my mind, I got there first, but the guy seemed mad. I gave the kid the ball, didn’t apologize and walked away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://giphy.com/embed/8c9JXDINO5TMnaBGkn&#34; width=&#34;480&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; frameBorder=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;giphy-embed&#34; allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://giphy.com/gifs/sunnyfxx-sunny-its-always-in-philadelphia-8c9JXDINO5TMnaBGkn&#34;&gt;via GIPHY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That underlines the issue with foul ball hunting at CCBL games; the pack of kids doing exactly the same thing. There was always a gaggle of children of various ages running around in the woods, parking lot and standing areas hunting baseballs. It got nasty on occasion; my hip check was a minor offense in comparison. Wrestling for foul balls in the grass was commonplace. But after watching and running and failing for years, I got my shot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a during a night game, but the sun was still high enough to allow for chases into the woods. I was lingering near the press box behind home plate, hoping for a player to pop a ball backwards into my lap. Soon enough, I heard the aluminum ping and watched a ball flying foul out to the right, well over the stands and into the woods. Charging around the batting cages and towards the woods with my little sister right behind me, I thought I was too late. Half a dozen kids were already picking through the brush. Still, I dove in there after them. Prickers nipped at my shins as I stomped around, hoping to feel the ball under my feet. Suddenly, a glimpse of something white. I shot my hand out at the object, feeling the familiar seams and leathery exterior as I closed my fingers around it. I didn’t yell or celebrate; just a quick “I got it!” to call off the hunters and to claim my long-awaited prize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All things considered, fishing a ball out of the woods at a college summer ball game played in front of 400 people is about as unimpressive as it gets. But at the time, I couldn’t have been prouder. Something I fixated on for years came to pass, and it was all because of me. I found the ball in the woods, which in my kid brain meant I was the best and a winner. As I got older, I came to the unfortunate realization that foul balls are worthless (and that I am not the best, or a winner). As far as I know, only Foul Ball Guy has managed a living catching them. And yet, adults will fling themselves down three rows of seats just to get a whiff. I contend that’s their kid brain waking up, remembering how excited it used to get in these moments and just shoving the adult brain out of the way so the actual adult can shove children out of the way. The older you get, chasing foul balls becomes harder to justify. But that doesn’t mean it’s not fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/gfMQ9JwaShY&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baseball Cards are Survivors</title>
      <link>https://thepileTKSM.com/rants-and-stories/cards-i-used-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 02:37:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thepileTKSM.com/rants-and-stories/cards-i-used-to-know/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Baseball cards are one of the few “relics” that remain popular, both with nostalgics, a bit with modern kids and now, via a leap online, NFTs (I’m not talking about those because I don’t know enough). There aren’t many others; bikes and skateboards come to mind, dolls and dollhouses too, I&amp;rsquo;m sure there are more. But even I, someone who mostly grew up in the 21st century, feel like an old man when thinking about what kids are raised on today. I never had video games (because of my parents), wasn’t really on the internet until middle school and walked around with a flip phone in my pocket until high school. My sister, three years younger, had a smartphone by the time she got to 9th grade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact that the baseball card, and the sports card in general, made it to my generation is a minor miracle. Baseball has been badly outstripped by football and basketball in the minds, lives and feeds of American kids. I can’t speak much on modern children considering I have none, but I imagine sports cards don’t quite match up to Candy Crush or an Xbox. And yet, they survive. I can appreciate its timeless appeal for a kid that loves sports with the cool pictures, stats, collector’s appeal. But you can’t play games on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember the first pack of cards I got. It was an old box set of 100+ from the late 80s/early 90s made of the flimsy, papery material that was the norm back then. My dad picked them up from Ocean State Job Lot. For those unfamiliar, the Lot is basically a Walmart with weirder, cheaper stuff. Finding a box of 25-year-old baseball cards is par for the course. I’d say they couldn’t have cost more than $10.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-qf3qrd2qpw&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;An actual ad they did&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At that point, I was eight or nine years old and a full-blown Red Sox fan following their curse–busting World Series win in ’04. Of course, I had no idea who any of the players in the old set were. I recognized Tony Gwynn, but only because &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sandiegouniontribune.com/name-drop-san-diego/story/2020-07-21/tony-gwynn-jr-name-drop-san-diego-podcast&#34;&gt;his son was playing in the MLB&lt;/a&gt; by that point. But my love for cards arose from something else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not long after I got that first set, one of my parents came home with a binder. Inside the binder were plastic pages with 12 little sleeves on them. Far from a child prodigy, I was confused about their purpose. They were for the cards and, newly enlightened, I set about organizing. I found countless ways to sort and order the cards; by team, color, position, last name and more. As I expanded my collection beyond baseball, I got more binders. Still, they were all dwarfed by the mammoth two-incher stuffed to the brim with random baseball players.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By then, I had advanced to current players. At the time (roughly ’05-’08), Topps were the easiest to find, so that’s what I bought. There were two card stores I frequented, both of which went under by 2010. They were little holes-in-the-wall, one on Main Street in Melrose and the other at the top of the Neck in Fairhaven. They were remarkably similar in layout and merchandise; long, narrow rooms filled with sports memorabilia and other relevant odds and ends. I would beg my dad to take me in each time we drove by, and he often would. A pack of cards was cheap (maybe $7), so the collection grew quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/1rOWt7C6o0U?start=161&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would spend hours on the floor sorting. Each time a new pack or set arrived, all the cards had to come out. I would create little piles on the living room carpet based on that day’s organizational technique. It was a good activity for muggy summer days when going outside meant heatstroke wasn’t far off. It would take hours, but I was totally engrossed. Occasionally, I found trade partners (like real baseball!). I’d take a stack of players on the block over to friend’s houses and start dealing. I’d like to think I made some shrewd moves in my day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After amassing a sizable collection, I decided to figure out what it was worth. Being a child and knowing nothing about card collecting or sales, I assumed quantity equated to value. I received a card index from a relative for my birthday and set about totaling up my collection. As I soon realized, most of the cards I owned were worth a whopping…10 cents. The most valuable one I had was a Nomar (Nomahhhhhh) Cubs card that had a piece of his bat embedded. That went for a tasty…five dollars. All told, the collection was basically worthless. They’re still in my childhood bedroom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://thepileTKSM.com/gif/nomar-garciaparra-batting-routine-oRWWnW&#34; title=&#34;Nomar Garciaparra batting routine&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.makeagif.com/media/7-18-2020/oRWWnW.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Nomar Garciaparra batting routine&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;font-size:11px;&#34;&gt;make &lt;a href=&#34;https://thepileTKSM.com/&#34; title=&#34;make a gif&#34;&gt;sports GIFs&lt;/a&gt; like this at MakeaGif&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come to think of it, collecting baseball cards taught me a lot about organizing. As I progressed through school, I found I was much more put together than my peers when it came to tasks such as not losing homework. Can a direct line be drawn? Probably not, but it didn’t hurt. I’m sure kids everywhere could tell stories about the weird stuff they loved back in the day that somehow helped them down the road, and mine was baseball cards. And despite technology, despite the state of baseball, I reckon they’ll stick around a bit longer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Last Time I Didn&#39;t Make it to the Bathroom</title>
      <link>https://thepileTKSM.com/rants-and-stories/the-last-time-i-didn-t-make-it-to-the-bathroom/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 02:33:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thepileTKSM.com/rants-and-stories/the-last-time-i-didn-t-make-it-to-the-bathroom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Oddly enough, the last time I crapped myself occurred at a point in my life when I was in far better physical shape than I am now. Usually, as your health deteriorates, the ability to hold your solid waste also deteriorates. Defecating oneself is also a problem that mostly affects the two age groups at the tips of the human bell curve; infants and the elderly. A teenager, however, is thought to be approaching the prime of their physical powers and certainly not a likely candidate for such an episode. But, alas, life is funny sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before diving into my tale of misery and woe, a couple disclaimers. First, there is no shame in such an event ONCE EVERY FEW YEARS. Sh*t happens; we’ve all been marooned in traffic or on the train or somewhere inexplicably lacking a commode when that feeling hits. If nothing else, I hope you found a bathroom in the aftermath of your little accident to try and piece back together whatever remains of your pride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, skid marks do not count. I’m going to be talking about a complete bowel release, not a little rosebud left for the laundry. Finally, one more request. As you read this story, see if you can remember the last time (or any time, for that matter) that it happened to you. It’s a humorous way to sift through your memory because, as I’ve long maintained, poop is always funny.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe style=&#34;width: 100%; border: none; display: block; max-width: 420px; height: 320px;&#34; src=&#34;https://getyarn.io/yarn-clip/391c933a-b5ec-4188-a447-f1a034fe8bd4/embed?autoplay=false&#34;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In high school, I rowed competitively for four years; we raced in the fall and the spring, trained outside in the summer and spent winters on the machines in what was also the wrestling room. It was journey of mediocrity interspersed with brief flashes of brilliance that afforded me some neat opportunities to race in exotic locales such as St. Catherine’s, Ontario. For those who don’t know, SC sits just 20 minutes over the American border, meaning it is simply an extension of northwestern New York. But because it is technically Canada, the businesses you would expect to see in a similar American town were masquerading under pseudonyms. For example, SportChek is Dick’s Sporting Goods, Tim Horton’s is Dunkin’ Donuts. However, the one universal name brand store that will ultimately catalyze my little incident shone like a beacon in a wasteland of Canadian knockoffs, beckoning warmly to a hungry pack of American teenagers looking to eat as much as possible as quickly as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I am not a big chain pizza guy; I’ve spent most of my life in the Boston area and the Chicago area, two major metropolitan locations with actual pizza restaurants that serve actual pizza. In a pinch, I will absolutely indulge in some Domino’s, but again, not my thing. But this was our first night in Canada, nobody had a car, and we were traveling in a group of 20 on foot. With options and daylight dwindling, the red roof of Pizza Hut hove into view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be clear, this was the worst chain pizza restaurant I have ever been to–any brand, any state, any country. It took over an hour for them to make four calzones; four PIZZA HUT calzones. I don’t remember much about how it tasted, probably because I don’t want to. Let’s just assumed it sucked and keep moving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because we had been stuffed in the back of a van for 10 hours, I wolfed down my quadrant. I thought nothing of it until the next morning at 5 AM, when I found myself parked on the toilet pissing out of my ass. Now normally, ass pee can be managed with ease; don’t get too adventurous, plan your day carefully around locations with bathrooms you know and love, and wait for whatever it was that caused the brown rain to leave your system. In my experience, it’s a 12-to-24 hour phenomenon at the most and occasionally results in just two or three runny, loud dumps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;tenor-gif-embed&#34; data-postid=&#34;15063908&#34; data-share-method=&#34;host&#34; data-width=&#34;100%&#34; data-aspect-ratio=&#34;1.4821428571428572&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tenor.com/view/family-guy-peter-griffin-bathroom-run-hurry-gif-15063908&#34;&gt;Family Guy Peter Griffin GIF&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;https://tenor.com/search/familyguy-gifs&#34;&gt;Familyguy GIFs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;script type=&#34;text/javascript&#34; async src=&#34;https://tenor.com/embed.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the reason I was up at 5 AM was because I had to be on the water at 6 AM to practice for the week’s races. I wasn’t worried yet; it felt like I had eliminated most of the offending calzone on the first try, and my stomach wasn’t particularly sore. I figured I could make it two or three hours and thought nothing of it until the precise moment we pushed off the dock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those who have never sat in a rowing shell, there is no bathroom on board. You sit about six inches off the water in a boat just wider than your hips, and you have about three feet to operate front to back. The issues for me began there; I had nowhere to go. I couldn’t jump into the water, I couldn’t force the boat back to shore because practice time was at a premium, and I certainly couldn’t let it go. That meant sitting there trying to row (a fairly strenuous, full-body physical activity) and not think about the storm brewing in my lower intestine or the fact that I easily could have nipped off to the bathroom before we started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/KaUnKIsM2os&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the Pizza Hut calzone was far from finished with me, and about an hour into practice it was two-foot dropkicking the backdoor. I suffered silently, unable to do anything except clench as hard as I possibly could. It was exhausting work, and ten minutes from time I gave in. Even if I held on a bit longer, I would have lost it on the dock or on my way to the porta-potty. It was actually the best place for me to have a situation that day; because it was, of course, diarrhea , the viscosity and small size of the turd allowed it to be quickly washed off the deck of the boat with a couple big splashes of water. I rinsed down my legs and water bottle while I was at it, actually feeling pretty good about the whole thing heading to land. The black spandex hid the discoloration, the water washed away the evidence and the lake breeze took care of the smell. As I hustled around the staging area looking for a porta-potty, I really thought I might just get away with this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://gifer.com/embed/74qW&#34; width=480 height=384.000 frameBorder=&#34;0&#34; allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gifer.com&#34;&gt;via GIFER&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in the final, cruelest twist of fate, I had actually picked the worst place on planet earth to sh_t myself. The bathrooms at a sporting event are about as prehistoric as the modern man gets, but rowing regattas are a different animal because they bring the porta-potty into play. There were hundreds of teams at this race, each with dozens of athletes and coaches, and precisely zero indoor commodes. It was the first week of August, and like the country it tries so hard to imitate, Canada also gets very, very hot around that time of the year. There were MAYBE six plastic palaces within reach, and all of them had been marinating in the sun for several days at the mercy of rather large athletes consuming their body weight in carbs. It was, for lack of a better word, a sh_tstorm of epic proportions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first hopper I visited made me gag, and there was no toilet paper. That would become a recurring theme, so eventually I got desperate. There was still residue on my ass and my thighs, but I had nothing to wipe with. I ran back to my bag and grabbed the only article of clothing I could spare: my boxers. I boogied back over to the nearest potty and tried to wipe the (now dry) refuse off myself before launching the underwear, the spandex shorts I had been wearing and my socks into the toilet. I allowed myself a brief, ultimately premature, sigh of relief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Y4HSQKUAPKM&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;**i don&amp;rsquo;t have a workaround for this yet–I know it makes you watch it on YouTube. Does it for NFL clips, too. Anyway, this is the Steve-O porta-potty slingshot prank from Jackass 3D. It&amp;rsquo;s awesome and you&amp;rsquo;ve probably seen it but watch it again.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there were no visible signs of my ordeal, I had been missing for ten minutes and returned clearly free-balling in my gym shorts. Luckily for me, I was at a rowing event, a place where men can walk around naked save for a spandex diaper and nobody bats an eye. However, I quickly realized I needed to pass one more level before I could get a proper shower–the van ride back to the hotel. Remember, it’s August, and the van has been in the lot baking for three hours. I had been sitting in my own feces for the better part of an hour, and the extent of my cleaning was a rinse with muddy lake water followed by a quick wipe-down with a pair of thin boxers Packed into a hot van, that lingering smell bloomed. But my savior on this occasion was something I don’t think has ever benefitted me at any other time; the pungent, overwhelming body odor of the teenage male. Still, once the door closed, one sharp-nosed teammate was kind enough to point out, &amp;ldquo;It smells like sh*t in here.&amp;rdquo; I kept my head down, my shirt over my nose, and twenty minutes later I took another horrific dump before finally getting into the shower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To put a bow on this overwritten tale, nobody found out that the smell was me. Rather, nobody confronted me directly about it, even though I imagine the young man sitting behind me in the boat that day knew exactly what happened (he now works for Sean Hannity. I hope I got some crap on him). The calzone ravaged my lower intestine for the rest of the day and much of the next, but I wasn’t good enough to be rowing that often and managed to find a toilet each time brown rain entered the forecast. I have no idea what happened; I’m not lactose intolerant or allergic to any foods, so I&amp;rsquo;m going to place 100% of the blame on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/search?tbs=lf:1,lf_ui:4&amp;amp;tbm=lcl&amp;amp;sxsrf=ALeKk03psdbd78nkUMTXNIKp13zS6shL1w:1617155891319&amp;amp;q=pizza+hut+st.+catharines&amp;amp;rflfq=1&amp;amp;num=10&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwit28qTt9nvAhVIQkEAHRPfDDUQtgN6BAgEEAc#rlfi=hd:;si:2637743176620312297;mv:%5B%5B43.18351608613695,-79.23869773955003%5D,%5B43.17451886107085,-79.26058456511156%5D,null,%5B43.179017639325956,-79.2496411523308%5D,16%5D&#34;&gt;Pizza Hut in St. Catherine&amp;rsquo;s, Ontario&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most stories this long provide some sort of life lesson or deep insight into human nature, none of which I have handy. Still, I’ll do you the unnecessary courtesy of revealing what this little accident taught me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t be ashamed to poop yourself (once every few years, if nobody finds out).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be wary of chain pizza.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are never in total control of your own anus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
