<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hater of the Day on The Pile</title>
    <link>https://thepileTKSM.com/hater/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hater of the Day on The Pile</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 01:22:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://thepileTKSM.com/hater/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>HotD 3/16- The Grammy Committee</title>
      <link>https://thepileTKSM.com/hater/hotd-3-16-the-grammy-committee/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 01:22:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thepileTKSM.com/hater/hotd-3-16-the-grammy-committee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Easy target to start off this section, but Dabo Swinney hasn’t said anything stupid lately (the next time he does, he’s right here). I’m not a big award show guy, but I love music much more than I do movies or TV. I’d give both up to have music on my deserted island, if you will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, the Grammys were last night, and I could’ve cared less. Not an original stance, I concede, but there’s a reason for that. It’s not the lack of star power, it isn’t the lack of pageantry, it’s not the lack of performances or anything else about &lt;em&gt;the show. The show&lt;/em&gt; usually kicks ass–unlimited budget, biggest names, biggest stage, labels muscling their artists into noms and wins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Grammy Committee delegitimized their own award, to me, because I know it&amp;rsquo;s rigged. That&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;em&gt;fan&lt;/em&gt; perspective, because I&amp;rsquo;ve only ever known that side of the equation (clarinet lessons notwithstanding). I can&amp;rsquo;t speak for artists, but they&amp;rsquo;ve spoken about it plenty. In pretty clear language, too. In fact, an artist telling us about the Committee pulling something like this is why THEY&amp;rsquo;RE the ones up for an award (if you want to call it that). It’s not the whole story, but definitely the tipping point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way the situation with The Weeknd was handled sealed it for me, but the deal was done long ago. Here&amp;rsquo;s an interview he gave on the topic. How can you tell one of the maybe 5 musicians in the world right now that can do any event they want anywhere in the world that he must choose between the Super Bowl and the Grammys? As if. It was a ridiculous move made more flagrant by their subsequent blackballing of the man’s music at the “premier” music award show on the planet. Why else wouldn&amp;rsquo;t he be there?&amp;ldquo;Blinding Lights&amp;rdquo; was song of the year; I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure everybody with the financial means to license that song used it for something. I really liked the album myself; &amp;ldquo;Heartless&amp;rdquo; has to be one of my favorites from him ever, and I probably have half of the songs downloaded. It was a better-sounding, better-executed &lt;em&gt;Starboy&lt;/em&gt; with the huge single to match. &amp;ldquo;Blinding Lights&amp;rdquo; would&amp;rsquo;ve won Song of the Year–point, blank, period. Weeknd would&amp;rsquo;ve probably picked up another 2 or 3 to boot. But when the Grammys said jump and Weeknd didn’t say “How high?,” his music somehow loses its acclaim. For the committee, I suppose it&amp;rsquo;s because Weeknd just did the only live performance that can really rival the Grammys–the Super Bowl Halftime Show. But still, they got pissy and threw this fit, and they look like huge tools. They are, and they&amp;rsquo;ve always acted like it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being younger, my introduction to those signature Grammy sham moments was 2014. Kendrick had &lt;em&gt;GKMC&lt;/em&gt; up for Rap Album of the Year, along with &lt;em&gt;Nothing Was the Same&lt;/em&gt;, along with &lt;em&gt;Yeezus&lt;/em&gt;, along with a Jay-Z album. And then there was Macklemore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know the details, but &lt;em&gt;GKMC&lt;/em&gt; turned out to be a defining album of the decade, Kendrick went on to build Top Dawg into one of the best labels in the industry, Kanye is&amp;hellip;doing his thing, Jay is his own empire and Drake is well on his way. I had every album up for the award in my phone except the Macklemore one. I always hated &amp;ldquo;Thrift Shop&amp;rdquo; and it still gives me hives. &lt;em&gt;Magna Carta&lt;/em&gt; aside (remember, a mid Jay-Z album is still better than 75% of albums), the other three are classic entries in the catalogues of their respective icons. But the Grammys said Macklemore had album of the year. Even the man himself didn’t agree. To his credit, after the weird apology, Macklemore just kinda kept to himself. He quietly slid out of the public eye after the whole debacle and is enjoying life as a family man and father. He also has a pretty nice golf swing. Good for you, Mack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to 2021, and it’s the same dirty diaper, different day. The hip-hop and R&amp;amp;B genres have largely distanced themselves from the award (i.e. they don&amp;rsquo;t show up and tweet things like &amp;ldquo;F*ck the Grammys&amp;rdquo;), but that doesn’t make it meaningless. It’s a goal for lots of artists, it takes a lot to even be considered at that level and there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of history there. The winners are typically deserving, it&amp;rsquo;s produced some legendary performances but that’s about all I’ve got in the way of compliments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being run by white people, the Grammys have managed to distance themselves from the genre that dictates culture, defines what is cool, influences how other genres sound like no other and will have the most staying power with future generations. It’s a long-winded way of saying if young music lovers don’t care now, imagine how little they’ll care in a decade. Artists can keep boycotting&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But again, this all stems from THE COMMITTEE. These are the people who decide why and how horrendous decisions continue to be made. Who calls the shots can and will change, but right now it&amp;rsquo;s just another chapter in the story of the committee flipping the collective bird. They are my Haters of the Day because of their willful ignorance. They hear all this (from the people/artists, not me) and continue doing the exact same thing. They’ll always get viewers from the award show watcher freaks, but it’s a music award. Music fans should care. They don’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Editor&amp;rsquo;s Post Script (3/22/21): I listened to a podcast that made a nuanced observation about this year&amp;rsquo;s show that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t considered. While making the point that this year&amp;rsquo;s event was a showcase of Black excellence, the podcast host pointed out how the record labels flipped the script on the committee this year. Yes, the voting board had the final say on who won, but the labels with the power muscled their artists onto the stage.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/joebuddenpodcast/episode-424-the-nine&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Check out the episode here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;(Grammys convo begins around the 20-minute mark).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
