<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hater of the Day on The Pile</title>
    <link>https://thepileTKSM.com/hater/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hater of the Day on The Pile</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 01:07:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://thepileTKSM.com/hater/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>HotD 4/21- John Henry</title>
      <link>https://thepileTKSM.com/hater/hotd-4-21-john-henry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 01:07:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thepileTKSM.com/hater/hotd-4-21-john-henry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was only a matter of time before this loser found himself here, but it’s not for the reason I would’ve thought. For those unaware, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_W._Henry&#34;&gt;John Henry&lt;/a&gt; is the elfish owner of the Boston Red Sox, Liverpool FC, the Boston Globe, Roush Fenway Racing, NESN and a whole host of other crap he doesn’t need. According to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_W._Henry&#34;&gt;ever-reliable Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;, his net worth checks in a shade under $3 billion in the year of our Lord 2000 and then 21.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/jo8S4tBQPJE&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Henry was in the news this week for trying to destroy European soccer. I’d be out of my depth trying to explain that debacle, but luckily The Athletic’s Adam Crafton has you covered; &lt;a href=&#34;https://theathletic.com/2532213/2021/04/20/dont-be-fooled-the-super-league-clubs-gambled-everything-and-they-blew-it/&#34;&gt;this piece&lt;/a&gt; is a good place to start. But I wanted to zero in on Henry specifically because this level of greed, disregard for his team’s fanbase and general air of shameless self-interest is nothing new to the good people of the Greater Boston area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I won’t really talk about his destruction of The Boston Globe since the paper was well on its way to irrelevancy by the time he purchased it in 2013. It had lost &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2013/08/04/business/media/new-york-times-company-sells-boston-globe.html&#34;&gt;90% of its value in the 20 years&lt;/a&gt; before the sale. The M.O. in recent years for the billionaire/hedge fund crowd has been as follows; purchase a struggling newspaper, cut staff, milk for ad revenue and discard when the last drops have been wrung from the cloth. Though Henry’s process is taking a bit longer, that’s where things are headed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But because Henry’s in the news for attempting another cash grab with a sports franchise as his vehicle, I’d like to talk about the Red Sox. Henry bought the team after selling the Marlins in 2002 and, not long after, broke the 86-year-old Curse of the Bambino in 2004. That’s one of two good things he’s done; the other was &lt;a href=&#34;https://chowderandchampions.com/2016/05/16/red-sox-fenway-park-nearly-torn/&#34;&gt;preventing the demolition of Fenway Park&lt;/a&gt; in 2012. The park could use some updates, but it shouldn’t be bulldozed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Z6_1Tb6wJHE&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shoutout to longtime Sox radio play-by-play man Joe Castiglione on the call–this is my favorite and one I can still recite word for word.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though Henry’s reign has netted World Series win in ’04, ’07, ’13 and ’18, we’ve also had our share of lowlights. That includes last-place AL East finishes in ’12, ’14, ’15 and ’20, the September 2011 collapse, followed by the Bobby Valentine chicken n’ beer season (scroll down a bit for the video) and a murder’s row of bad free agency signings. I’ll get to those in a second, but last year was particularly egregious. I think, and hope, that this year’s squad will redeem some of what we saw last year, but 2020 was unwatchable. If you, as the billionaire owner, demonstrate you don’t care by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.baseball-almanac.com/teamstats/roster.php?y=2020&amp;amp;t=BOS&#34;&gt;trotting that roster&lt;/a&gt; out there, then how can you expect the fans to care? I’ll put on my Boston sports douche hat for a second to say we expect, and deserve, better. In the only terms Henry knows–dollars and cents–the Red Sox are &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gq.com.au/fitness/sport/these-are-the-20-most-valuable-sports-teams-in-the-world-for-2020/image-gallery/3627783a282f8891b26e84fa10dcba70?pos=16&#34;&gt;one of the most valuable franchises&lt;/a&gt; in the world. Your job, as the owner with endless pockets, is to give us something to watch. I don’t care about COVID, I don’t care about the payroll, I don’t care about you losing money. There are zero excuses for putting a team like that on the field under any circumstances, especially when fans desperately needed something to watch and a team to get behind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/jfCedWH3AP8&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This was the most interesting thing that happened to the Red Sox in 2020&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the free agent side of things, that’s where we entered unforgivable territory. There were a couple bad ones from the late 2000s, but things really kicked off with &lt;a href=&#34;https://bleacherreport.com/articles/1557988-carl-crawfords-comments-just-show-he-was-a-bad-fit-for-the-boston-red-sox&#34;&gt;Carl Crawford&lt;/a&gt;. That was a seven-year, $142 million deal, and we only saw Carl for two of those years. His final play was&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hz_zf4ee1_0&#34;&gt; botching a line drive to left field&lt;/a&gt;, capping off the historic September 2011 collapse. Next up: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.boston.com/sports/boston-red-sox/2019/08/12/pablo-sandoval-red-sox-free-agent-mocking-comments&#34;&gt;Pablo Sandoval&lt;/a&gt; for five years and $90 million. There was the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/early-lead/wp/2015/06/18/some-are-wondering-if-pablo-sandoval-was-on-instagram-during-a-red-sox-game/&#34;&gt;Instagram scandal&lt;/a&gt;, the year where he only played three games and, in the end, 161 games of piss poor play over 3 seasons. Even David Price for seven years and $217 million (yes, over $200 mill) was awful. He was great in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gq8veYjEC64&#34;&gt;the 2018 playoffs/World Series&lt;/a&gt;, but not $217 million great. He lasted four seasons, which was fantastic considering the company he’s keeping here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/EqFBLlXltzo&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given Henry’s eagerness to throw gobs of money at other team’s stars, blasting through the tax ceiling in the process, you’d think he’d do so for Mookie. But the second a homegrown talent revealed himself to be a generational talent, that’s when Henry decided to tighten the purse strings. He was so uncomfortable with the idea of paying someone already on his books the MLB equivalent of a max deal that he shipped that player across the country. Come to think of it, the fact that it was the Dodgers who had the wherewithal to dump a huge deal in his lap is the biggest condemnation of all. It would&amp;rsquo;ve been worse if it were the Yankees, of course, but the only the Dodgers exist on the same financial level as BOS/NYY. They want to be THE franchise, and they already had the World Series-winning roster. Even if they lost everyone else, they have a superstar to lead their team through the next decade. The Red Sox, on the other hand, let that player walk away. The most heartbreaking part of the deal was nobody wanted it to happen; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cbssports.com/mlb/news/red-sox-hall-of-famer-jim-rice-says-mookie-betts-didnt-want-to-leave-boston/&#34;&gt;Mookie wanted to stay&lt;/a&gt;, the fans wanted him to stay, but John f*cking Henry didn’t want to pay. It &amp;ldquo;makes sense&amp;rdquo; from a financial standpoint, but c&amp;rsquo;mon. After years of spending like there was no tomorrow, he got cheap with the only once-in-a-blue-moon talent (Papi and maybe Manny aside) that he’s ever had as owner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/g59FR48AJNM&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s exactly why none of the European Super League stuff is surprising. John Henry has already demonstrated he doesn’t care about the fans, the teams, the history, what it means to people, or anything beyond his bottom line. The only reason he saved Fenway is because he was already raking people over the coals for the privilege of attending. Sadly, it&amp;rsquo;s par for the course. Again, I’m out of my depth on the ESL debate, but the obvious silver lining to me is the fact that the fans demonstrated their immense power. Somehow, even the JP Morgan asswipes called in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2021/04/23/sports/soccer/jpmorgan-super-league.html&#34;&gt;to forecast the repetitional consequences&lt;/a&gt; of the move failed to account for the team’s fans turning on the owners. I can only hope American sports fans find that energy and keep it, with soulless, greedy, malignant, idiotic owners like John Henry moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/LQ1z_MRdj3M&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;American sports fans–more of this!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HotD 3/16- The Grammy Committee</title>
      <link>https://thepileTKSM.com/hater/hotd-3-16-the-grammy-committee/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 01:22:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thepileTKSM.com/hater/hotd-3-16-the-grammy-committee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Easy target to start off this section, but Dabo Swinney &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.espn.com/video/clip/_/id/17552638&#34;&gt;hasn’t said anything stupid lately&lt;/a&gt; (the next time he does, he’s right here). I’m not a big award show guy, but I love music much more than I do movies or TV. I’d give both up to have music on my deserted island, if you will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, the Grammys were last night, and I could’ve cared less. Not an original stance, I concede, but there’s a reason for that. It’s not the lack of star power, it isn’t the lack of pageantry, it’s not the lack of performances or anything else about &lt;em&gt;the show. The show&lt;/em&gt; usually kicks ass–unlimited budget, biggest names, biggest stage, labels muscling their artists into noms and wins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/bEe2ohaO8BA&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Grammy Committee delegitimized their own award, to me, because I know it&amp;rsquo;s rigged. That&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;em&gt;fan&lt;/em&gt; perspective, because I&amp;rsquo;ve only ever known that side of the equation (clarinet lessons notwithstanding). I can&amp;rsquo;t speak for artists, but &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mensxp.com/culture/music/86511-grammys-under-fire-racism-zayn-bts-the-weeknd.html&#34;&gt;they&amp;rsquo;ve spoken about it plenty&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://theundefeated.com/features/dj-jazzy-jeff-the-fresh-prince-and-a-grammy-boycott-that-set-the-tone-for-three-more-decades-of-rap-and-culture/&#34;&gt;In pretty clear language&lt;/a&gt;, too. In fact, an artist telling us about the Committee pulling something like this is why I put virtual ink to virtual paper. It’s not the whole story, but definitely the tipping point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way the situation with The Weeknd was handled sealed it for me, but the deal was done long ago. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodhousekeeping.com/life/entertainment/a35809227/why-is-weeknd-boycotting-grammys-2021-nomination-snub/&#34;&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a pretty good rundown&lt;/a&gt; (by Good Housekeeping, no less!) that touches on the ultimatum issued by the committee. How can you tell one of the maybe 5 musicians in the world right now that can do any event they want anywhere in the world that he must choose between the Super Bowl and the Grammys? As if. It was a ridiculous move made more flagrant by their subsequent blackballing of the man’s music at the “premier” music award show on the planet. Why else wouldn&amp;rsquo;t he be there?&amp;ldquo;Blinding Lights&amp;rdquo; was song of the year; I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure everybody with the financial means to license that song used it for something. I really liked the album myself; &amp;ldquo;Heartless&amp;rdquo; has to be one of my favorites from him ever, and I probably have half of the songs downloaded. It was a better-sounding, better-executed &lt;em&gt;Starboy&lt;/em&gt; with the huge single to match. &amp;ldquo;Blinding Lights&amp;rdquo; would&amp;rsquo;ve won Song of the Year–point, blank, period. Weeknd would&amp;rsquo;ve probably picked up another 2 or 3 to boot. But when the Grammys said jump and Weeknd didn’t say “how high?,” his music somehow loses its acclaim. For the committee, I suppose it&amp;rsquo;s because Weeknd just did the only live performance that can really rival the Grammys–the Super Bowl Halftime Show. But still, they got pissy and threw this fit, and they look like huge tools. They are, and they&amp;rsquo;ve always acted like it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/1DpH-icPpl0&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being younger, my introduction to those signature Grammy sham moments was 2013. Kendrick had &lt;em&gt;GKMC&lt;/em&gt; up for Rap Album of the Year, along with &lt;em&gt;Nothing Was the Same&lt;/em&gt;, along with &lt;em&gt;Yeezus&lt;/em&gt;, along with a Jay-Z album. And then there was Macklemore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know the details, but &lt;em&gt;GKMC&lt;/em&gt; turned out to be a defining album of the decade, Kendrick went on to build Top Dawg into one of the best labels in the industry, Kanye is&amp;hellip;doing his thing, Jay is his own empire and Drake is well on his way. I had every album up for the award in my phone except the Macklemore one. I always hated &amp;ldquo;Thrift Shop&amp;rdquo; and it still gives me hives. &lt;em&gt;Magna Carta&lt;/em&gt; aside (remember, a mid Jay-Z album is still better than 75% of albums), the other three are classic entries in the catalogues of their respective icons. But the Grammys said Macklemore had album of the year. Even the man himself didn’t agree. To his credit, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cbsnews.com/news/grammys-2014-macklemore-apologizes-to-kendrick-lamar-after-best-rap-album-win/&#34;&gt;after the weird apology&lt;/a&gt;, Macklemore just kinda kept to himself. He quietly slid out of the public eye after the whole debacle and is enjoying life as a family man and father. He also has a pretty nice golf swing. Good for you, Mack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to 2021, and it’s the same dirty diaper, different day. The hip-hop and R&amp;amp;B genres have largely distanced themselves from the award (i.e. they don&amp;rsquo;t show up and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vulture.com/2021/03/zayn-malik-tweets-f-the-grammys-clarifies-criticisms.html&#34;&gt;tweet things like &amp;ldquo;F*ck the Grammys&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;), but that doesn’t make it meaningless. It’s a goal for lots of artists, it takes a lot to even be considered at that level and there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of history there. The winners are typically deserving and it&amp;rsquo;s produced some legendary performances (2021 included).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://giphy.com/embed/E61W5osNXK0Xq8aY6h&#34; width=&#34;480&#34; height=&#34;267&#34; frameBorder=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;giphy-embed&#34; allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://giphy.com/gifs/recordingacademy-grammys-2021-E61W5osNXK0Xq8aY6h&#34;&gt;via GIPHY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being run by white people, the Grammys have managed to distance themselves from the genre that dictates culture, defines what is cool, influences how other genres sound like no other and will have the most staying power with future generations. It’s a long-winded way of saying if young music lovers don’t care now, imagine how little they’ll care in a decade. Artists can keep boycotting&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But again, this all stems from THE COMMITTEE. These are the people who decide why and how horrendous decisions continue to be made. Who calls the shots can and will change, but right now it&amp;rsquo;s just another chapter in the story of the committee flipping the collective bird. They are my Haters of the Day because of their willful ignorance. They hear endless amounts of valid criticism from artists and fans, only to continue doing the exact same thing in the face of intensified scrutiny. . They’ll always get viewers, but the premier matters less and less to music fans with each passing year. How will that bode for its future?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/LTPqtO5EbFk&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
