<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hater of the Day on The Pile</title>
    <link>https://thepileTKSM.com/hater/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hater of the Day on The Pile</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 01:19:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://thepileTKSM.com/hater/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>HotD 4/1 - People Who Got Mad About the Lil Nas X Video</title>
      <link>https://thepileTKSM.com/hater/hotd-3-29-god-fearing-americans/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 01:19:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thepileTKSM.com/hater/hotd-3-29-god-fearing-americans/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll make this quick(ish) since Lil Nas X&amp;rsquo;s new music video for &amp;ldquo;MONTERO (Call Me By Your Name)&amp;rdquo; is all over the socials at the moment. Sparknotes version: he descends a stripper pole into hell, red braids swirling around him, to shake ass in the devil&amp;rsquo;s face while wearing thigh-high leather boots and what I call ball-huggers (brief-style men&amp;rsquo;s underwear). I&amp;rsquo;d suggest watching it for yourself; there&amp;rsquo;s a lot going on, and it&amp;rsquo;s all very entertaining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/6swmTBVI83k&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Predictably, the self-appointed gatekeepers of all that is holy and American fired up the faux outrage machine. Nothing new from the right; use Christianity as a weapon to be racist/homophobic under the guise of &amp;ldquo;protecting our children&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;restoring traditional American values.&amp;rdquo; That&amp;rsquo;s a separate can of worms I won&amp;rsquo;t open right now, but as is custom in this section, I wanted to take some time to hate on two of the haters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The appetizer here is Kristi Noem, the brain-dead, gun-toting governor of South Dakota. Last week she &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nraila.org/articles/20210324/south-dakota-governor-noem-signs-multiple-pro-gun-bills-into-law&#34;&gt;expanded gun rights&lt;/a&gt; in the wake of two mass shootings, this week she &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cnn.com/2021/03/30/politics/south-dakota-transgender-sports-kristi-noem/index.html&#34;&gt;cooked up an executive order&lt;/a&gt; barring transgender athletes from participating in K-12 girls sports (in other words, trans women aren&amp;rsquo;t women in South Dakota), but she spent the Lord&amp;rsquo;s Day #owning the libs. Unable to help herself or find something to do beyond being a discriminatory, narrow-minded sack of sh*t, she fired off this snappy little number.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Our kids are being told that this kind of product is, not only okay, it&#39;s &#34;exclusive.&#34; But do you know what&#39;s more exclusive? Their God-given eternal soul.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;We are in a fight for the soul of our nation. We need to fight hard. And we need to fight smart. We have to win. &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/m1k1YWFpuo&#34;&gt;https://t.co/m1k1YWFpuo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Governor Kristi Noem (@govkristinoem) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/govkristinoem/status/1376239196709478400?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;March 28, 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, Kristi, these are fire. I&amp;rsquo;ve always loved 97s. Second of all, God-given eternal soul? I hate to be the bearer of bad news, but if we&amp;rsquo;re talking souls, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thedailybeast.com/gov-kristi-noem-says-shes-celebrating-intl-womens-day-by-signing-anti-trans-bill&#34;&gt;yours is not in the greatest of shape&lt;/a&gt;. Just type &amp;ldquo;Kristi Noem scandal&amp;rdquo; into Google for more (mostly &lt;a href=&#34;https://prospect.org/power/noem-bill-would-make-dark-money-disclosure-illegal/&#34;&gt;misusing taxpayer dollars&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aberdeennews.com/news/opinion/from-about-41k-to-58k-for-governor-s-daughter/article_fc637b86-1dbc-11ea-b961-db14b62c3554.html&#34;&gt;giving a raise to her daughter&lt;/a&gt; while bemoaning budget issues and &lt;a href=&#34;https://dakotafreepress.com/2019/06/16/girls-stater-expelled-after-posting-photo-of-noem-and-anti-trump-message/&#34;&gt;bullying high schoolers&lt;/a&gt;). Funny, I&amp;rsquo;m seeing lots of money-related transgressions in there–what was it the Bible said about the rich man getting into Heaven? If this is what &amp;ldquo;fight hard, fight smart&amp;rdquo; looks like, I think the rest of us are gonna be just fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the real treat is poopy pants gun girl. I don&amp;rsquo;t know how to spell her name (Caytlin? Kaytlyn? Kaiytliyn?), but I like PPGG as an acronym. Anyway, she hit a triple word score in her responses–racism, homophobia (tweeting &amp;ldquo;At least I can procreate&amp;rdquo;) and Karen-esque victimhood. She&amp;rsquo;s saying the quiet parts out loud again! All Lil Nas X did was call her shitty pants, and PPGG, like the good Karen she is, huffed and puffed and&amp;hellip;jumped off the porch with racism. And for funzies, she claimed Lil Nas X &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/kaitmarieox/status/1376375609555886080&#34;&gt;threatened to rape her father&lt;/a&gt;. Karening at its finest; find a way to make yourself the victim in a fight you started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Do you still see your dad? &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/yZhocQvvE5&#34;&gt;https://t.co/yZhocQvvE5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Kaitlin Bennett (@KaitMarieox) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/KaitMarieox/status/1376364462911987712?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;March 29, 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are people really this dumb? I know they are, but we&amp;rsquo;ve been having this conversation since before I was born. MUSIC is ART, it is a medium for SELF EXPRESSION. Lil Nas X is an artist who has made it abundantly clear he can, and will, do whatever he damn well pleases. Children will consume art, music especially, and connect with whatever resonates with them. Also, FWIW, Lil Nas X snaps the devil&amp;rsquo;s neck at the end of the video–he defeated Satan by distracting him with ass. Kristi and PPGG aren&amp;rsquo;t with killing the devil? The soul of this nation may truly be unsafe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/sLSorLH-FEg&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a rollout, folks; bad press is still good press, and this isn&amp;rsquo;t even bad press–the video is dope. None of the outraged parties would&amp;rsquo;ve known about or given a second thought to this song, video, the shoes, etc. if their sh&lt;em&gt;tty little interns hadn&amp;rsquo;t tucked it away for faux-outrage Monday. Yes, it&amp;rsquo;s just one of the countless side effects of American culture/politics, but this particular meaningless debate is &lt;em&gt;decades&lt;/em&gt; old. We did this dance with jazz, then rock, then metal, then hip-hop. WE DID IT TWO MONTHS AGO WITH &amp;ldquo;WAP.&amp;rdquo; So of course it stands to reason that the &amp;ldquo;Old Town Road&amp;rdquo; guy face-f&lt;/em&gt;cking the devil will be the end of us all. And you&amp;rsquo;re going to hell if you liked anything about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lil Nas X usually walks the line well between trolling and making a point, and I think he&amp;rsquo;s at it again. I&amp;rsquo;d imagine people have been telling LNX he&amp;rsquo;s going to hell ever since he came out as gay (or even before). To me, he flipped that notion on its head and went to hell, shall we say, on his terms. He described this song as &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/CM3i2RelCkK/&#34;&gt;a love letter to his younger self&lt;/a&gt;, so that all seems to check out. The video was clearly well-conceived, and it seems like a cathartic moment for LNX. At the same time, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/LilNasX/status/1376568409295491081&#34;&gt;he told us this was a rollout&lt;/a&gt;. LNX came up on Twitter; he&amp;rsquo;s punching down to these clueless, humorless, soulless asswipes. His responses are &lt;em&gt;extremely&lt;/em&gt; benign compared to what&amp;rsquo;s being said about him. But you need attention to capitalize on your talent these days, and LNX is doing just that. Stir sh*t, sell records, and if you don&amp;rsquo;t like it, tough toodles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This won&amp;rsquo;t be a story next week. The right will have moved on to something equally banal and unproductive, and the left will do the same. But stop doing this to music–nobody&amp;rsquo;s making anybody listen to anything. Political music can be great and add a lot to larger conversations, but this is a pop song with some wild visuals. Lo and behold, he&amp;rsquo;s not even the first musician to use Satanic imagery. Let artists create what they want, let people enjoy what resonates with them and, to borrow a talking point from the GOP, mind your business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/pqK-J9S2GXs&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HotD 3/16- The Grammy Committee</title>
      <link>https://thepileTKSM.com/hater/hotd-3-16-the-grammy-committee/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 01:22:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thepileTKSM.com/hater/hotd-3-16-the-grammy-committee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Easy target to start off this section, but Dabo Swinney &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.espn.com/video/clip/_/id/17552638&#34;&gt;hasn’t said anything stupid lately&lt;/a&gt; (the next time he does, he’s right here). I’m not a big award show guy, but I love music much more than I do movies or TV. I’d give both up to have music on my deserted island, if you will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, the Grammys were last night, and I could’ve cared less. Not an original stance, I concede, but there’s a reason for that. It’s not the lack of star power, it isn’t the lack of pageantry, it’s not the lack of performances or anything else about &lt;em&gt;the show. The show&lt;/em&gt; usually kicks ass–unlimited budget, biggest names, biggest stage, labels muscling their artists into noms and wins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/bEe2ohaO8BA&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Grammy Committee delegitimized their own award, to me, because I know it&amp;rsquo;s rigged. That&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;em&gt;fan&lt;/em&gt; perspective, because I&amp;rsquo;ve only ever known that side of the equation (clarinet lessons notwithstanding). I can&amp;rsquo;t speak for artists, but &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mensxp.com/culture/music/86511-grammys-under-fire-racism-zayn-bts-the-weeknd.html&#34;&gt;they&amp;rsquo;ve spoken about it plenty&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://theundefeated.com/features/dj-jazzy-jeff-the-fresh-prince-and-a-grammy-boycott-that-set-the-tone-for-three-more-decades-of-rap-and-culture/&#34;&gt;In pretty clear language&lt;/a&gt;, too. In fact, an artist telling us about the Committee pulling something like this is why I put virtual ink to virtual paper. It’s not the whole story, but definitely the tipping point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way the situation with The Weeknd was handled sealed it for me, but the deal was done long ago. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodhousekeeping.com/life/entertainment/a35809227/why-is-weeknd-boycotting-grammys-2021-nomination-snub/&#34;&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a pretty good rundown&lt;/a&gt; (by Good Housekeeping, no less!) that touches on the ultimatum issued by the committee. How can you tell one of the maybe 5 musicians in the world right now that can do any event they want anywhere in the world that he must choose between the Super Bowl and the Grammys? As if. It was a ridiculous move made more flagrant by their subsequent blackballing of the man’s music at the “premier” music award show on the planet. Why else wouldn&amp;rsquo;t he be there?&amp;ldquo;Blinding Lights&amp;rdquo; was song of the year; I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure everybody with the financial means to license that song used it for something. I really liked the album myself; &amp;ldquo;Heartless&amp;rdquo; has to be one of my favorites from him ever, and I probably have half of the songs downloaded. It was a better-sounding, better-executed &lt;em&gt;Starboy&lt;/em&gt; with the huge single to match. &amp;ldquo;Blinding Lights&amp;rdquo; would&amp;rsquo;ve won Song of the Year–point, blank, period. Weeknd would&amp;rsquo;ve probably picked up another 2 or 3 to boot. But when the Grammys said jump and Weeknd didn’t say “how high?,” his music somehow loses its acclaim. For the committee, I suppose it&amp;rsquo;s because Weeknd just did the only live performance that can really rival the Grammys–the Super Bowl Halftime Show. But still, they got pissy and threw this fit, and they look like huge tools. They are, and they&amp;rsquo;ve always acted like it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/1DpH-icPpl0&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being younger, my introduction to those signature Grammy sham moments was 2013. Kendrick had &lt;em&gt;GKMC&lt;/em&gt; up for Rap Album of the Year, along with &lt;em&gt;Nothing Was the Same&lt;/em&gt;, along with &lt;em&gt;Yeezus&lt;/em&gt;, along with a Jay-Z album. And then there was Macklemore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know the details, but &lt;em&gt;GKMC&lt;/em&gt; turned out to be a defining album of the decade, Kendrick went on to build Top Dawg into one of the best labels in the industry, Kanye is&amp;hellip;doing his thing, Jay is his own empire and Drake is well on his way. I had every album up for the award in my phone except the Macklemore one. I always hated &amp;ldquo;Thrift Shop&amp;rdquo; and it still gives me hives. &lt;em&gt;Magna Carta&lt;/em&gt; aside (remember, a mid Jay-Z album is still better than 75% of albums), the other three are classic entries in the catalogues of their respective icons. But the Grammys said Macklemore had album of the year. Even the man himself didn’t agree. To his credit, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cbsnews.com/news/grammys-2014-macklemore-apologizes-to-kendrick-lamar-after-best-rap-album-win/&#34;&gt;after the weird apology&lt;/a&gt;, Macklemore just kinda kept to himself. He quietly slid out of the public eye after the whole debacle and is enjoying life as a family man and father. He also has a pretty nice golf swing. Good for you, Mack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to 2021, and it’s the same dirty diaper, different day. The hip-hop and R&amp;amp;B genres have largely distanced themselves from the award (i.e. they don&amp;rsquo;t show up and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vulture.com/2021/03/zayn-malik-tweets-f-the-grammys-clarifies-criticisms.html&#34;&gt;tweet things like &amp;ldquo;F*ck the Grammys&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;), but that doesn’t make it meaningless. It’s a goal for lots of artists, it takes a lot to even be considered at that level and there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of history there. The winners are typically deserving and it&amp;rsquo;s produced some legendary performances (2021 included).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://giphy.com/embed/E61W5osNXK0Xq8aY6h&#34; width=&#34;480&#34; height=&#34;267&#34; frameBorder=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;giphy-embed&#34; allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://giphy.com/gifs/recordingacademy-grammys-2021-E61W5osNXK0Xq8aY6h&#34;&gt;via GIPHY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being run by white people, the Grammys have managed to distance themselves from the genre that dictates culture, defines what is cool, influences how other genres sound like no other and will have the most staying power with future generations. It’s a long-winded way of saying if young music lovers don’t care now, imagine how little they’ll care in a decade. Artists can keep boycotting&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But again, this all stems from THE COMMITTEE. These are the people who decide why and how horrendous decisions continue to be made. Who calls the shots can and will change, but right now it&amp;rsquo;s just another chapter in the story of the committee flipping the collective bird. They are my Haters of the Day because of their willful ignorance. They hear endless amounts of valid criticism from artists and fans, only to continue doing the exact same thing in the face of intensified scrutiny. . They’ll always get viewers, but the premier matters less and less to music fans with each passing year. How will that bode for its future?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/LTPqtO5EbFk&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
