<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sports &amp; Games on The Pile</title>
    <link>https://thepileTKSM.com/sports-and-games/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sports &amp; Games on The Pile</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 21:25:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://thepileTKSM.com/sports-and-games/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>My Favorite Brand of (NBA) Rebuild </title>
      <link>https://thepileTKSM.com/sports-and-games/my-favorite-brand-of-nba-rebuild/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 21:25:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thepileTKSM.com/sports-and-games/my-favorite-brand-of-nba-rebuild/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ah, the rebuild. It can be a shame to witness as a fan, an even bigger shame when the front office doesn’t know how to handle it. There are degrees to the art; a full teardown and rebuild, on-the-fly in the mediocre zone, endless searching for complementary pieces, etc. The OKC Thunder are in the midst of a great one–outside looking in on the playoff picture, but with a play-in tourney ceiling, marked growth from their young star and a well-conceived supporting cast. The Suns deserve a mention here as well, but they&amp;rsquo;re enjoying their first season of truly being competitive. We’ll stick to the NBA for the purposes of this blog because the smaller roster size best illustrates my favorite type of rebuild.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/nPvhrO6YM1c&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cannot wait for SGA to make his first All-Star game in 2022&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that would be…those rare, beautiful seasons where your rebuild is just spare parts cast off from other rebuilds. There’s a couple ways to get here as a team, but it typically involves some combination of the following: young pieces that aren’t ready, limited cap space from bad contracts left over from aging stars/pieces, a need to “make something happen” (i.e. fill a roster). Maybe sprinkle in a new coach/GM, add a dash of underperforming holdovers, a pinch of low expectations and you’ve got the perfect scenario to bring in a bunch of spare parts and see what happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is it my favorite type of rebuild? Because it’s as close as we get to an actual island of misfit toys. It also produces some head-scratching rosters (think &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.basketball-reference.com/teams/DET/2021.html&#34;&gt;this season’s Pistons&lt;/a&gt;, last year&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.basketball-reference.com/teams/WAS/2020.html&#34;&gt;Wizards&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.basketball-reference.com/teams/NYK/2020.html&#34;&gt;Knicks&lt;/a&gt;). I go back to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.basketball-reference.com/teams/CHI/2019.html&#34;&gt;2018-19 Bulls&lt;/a&gt;, a team I watched far too much of, as an example. Their best player was Zack Lavine, who they got in the Jimmy Butler trade with Minnesota. Ditto for Kris Dunn, ditto for Lauri Markkanen (who they took with that Wolves pick). Aside from Wendell Carter Jr. and Chandler Hutchinson (both rookies), all contributors of note were castoffs from other rebuilds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/MdVTBGEuxhM&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I did game night media relations for the Bulls in &amp;lsquo;18-&amp;lsquo;19, and some of those early Boylen press conferences were BRUTAL. Dude is not the best at press conferences and beat writers were more or less laughing in his face after every loss. Can only image what it was like the following year.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Otto Porter Jr. came over midseason after the Wizards realized their window was being slammed shut and somehow decided Bobby Portis and Jabari Parker were the answer. TLC was a Process cast-off. Justin Holiday (an OG Processor) was back for a second stint after bopping around the league. Cam Payne and Robin Lopez were both consummate journeymen. Aside from Lopez, Holiday and Porter, nobody had more than 5 years NBA service at the start of the season. Oh, and they fired Fred Hoiberg (meh) midseason for Jim Boylen (much, much worse).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason you don’t build cars out of spare parts is because they run like ass and break down. Same rules apply to basketball teams; for that Bulls roster, 22-60 was how they ran. But there&amp;rsquo;s always someone in that zone. It takes a couple years, some bad decisions, the wrong people at the wheel and some bad luck, but it happens. At times, it’s a necessary evil; those high-priced dudes you shipped out need replacements, but you swung and missed at the top levels of free agency (hi 2010s Knicks, small market teams). Your lottery pick(s) isn’t ready, but he needs playing time. You want a strong bench to support your dream starting 5 down the road, but first you gotta see who out of the washed-up free agents and non-lottery draft picks are worth a flier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/c2gv3zSmMc4&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All that said, sometimes it works. I&amp;rsquo;m harkening again, this time back to one of my favorite teams–the 2016-17 Celtics. For those who forget, they somehow finished first in the East, finagled their way into the ECF and got blown out by year one of the LeBron Cavs 2.0. It’s not a perfect example; Brown (year 2), Tatum (rookie), Rozier, Avery Bradley and Olynk were all Boston draft picks, but everything really came together right between the post-Big 3 rock bottom phase and and the Tatum-Brown core of today. Al Horford was the first big name free agent to come to town in years, but only because he saw the writing on the wall for the Bud Hawks. Other than that, the rotation was filled out with a bunch of names that wouldn’t strike fear into many hearts; Jae Crowder, Tyler Zeller, Jonas Jerebko, Gerald Green and Amir Johnson all played A LOT of minutes. And then there’s Isaiah Thomas, jettisoned from the Suns rebuild (remember their &lt;a href=&#34;https://bleacherreport.com/articles/2246377-3-point-guard-lineup-is-best-blueprint-for-phoenix-suns-success&#34;&gt;triple point guard experiment?&lt;/a&gt;) only to have one of the most electric single seasons by a mediocre player in recent memory. Much of the credit goes to Brad Stevens for bringing the best out of that roster, but there’s something to be said for the players themselves making it work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then you have teams like last year&amp;rsquo;s Knicks. Let&amp;rsquo;s remove R.J. Barrett, Mitchell Robinson, Frank Ntilikina and Kevin Knox (I guess) from the equation as the &amp;ldquo;young core&amp;rdquo; and Julius Randle as a good signing that&amp;rsquo;s paying off tremendously this season. But the rest? Taj Gibson&amp;rsquo;s brightest days were with the D-Rose Bulls, but even Minnesota–another offender here–couldn&amp;rsquo;t bring themselves to give him minutes. Boston decided Marcus Morris Sr. too expensive, and he was out. Both the Bulls and Wizards deemed Bobby Portis unfit for their own rebuilds. Higher up the food chain, the Blazers had no time for Mo Harkless and the Magic did the same to Elfrid Payton. The PISTONS saw half a season of both Wayne Ellington and Reggie Bullock before concluding they were not the solution. Dennis Smith Jr.&amp;rsquo;s lack of staying power has been similarly well-documented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Point being, the spare parts rebuild usually goes poorly, but it’s not a death sentence. Hell, those seasons help you find a couple bench guys to tie your rotation together, give your draft picks some run (since the rest of your roster stinks) and teach your front office about failed rolls of the dice, both in the draft and free agency. When they stink, it’s expected, and if they overachieve, it’s a lot of fun as a fan. That volatility is what I love– never knowing what you’ll get, who’s going to win you a game, who’s cooked and who still has something left. Even as a Celtics fan today (and I&amp;rsquo;m sure plenty would agree), you get nostalgic for the surprisingly-good rebuild seasons, especially when later teams that are supposed to be good underperform. Knicks and Suns fans especially seem to be having those first fun years after a long rebuild, so be sure support them in their fun.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
